This should be in two tables, patients and treatments.
يجب أن يكون هذا في جدولين، المرضى والعلاجات.
Patients would be exactly the same in terms of these columns here.
سيكون جدول المرضى مطابق لهذا تمامًا من حيث هذه الأعمدة الموجودة هنا.
All 14 would remain.
سيظل عدد الأعمدة 14 عمود.
Then I'd argue that the adverse reaction column of the adverse reactions table,
ثم سأرجح أن عمود رد الفعل العكسي في جدول ردود الأفعال العكسية،
the very last one down here,
هو الأخير في الأسفل هنا،
I'd argue that this belongs in the treatments table.
سأرجح أن هذا ينتمي إلى جدول العلاجات.
If we want to look at treatment data,
إذا أردنا الاطلاع على بيانات العلاج،
the adverse reaction for that treatment is naturally connected.
فإن رد الفعل العكسي للعلاج يرتبط ارتباطًا طبيعيًا.
This is the same type of observational unit.
هذا هو نفس النوع لوحدة الملاحظات.
So because the other two columns in this adverse reactions table,
لذلك فإن العمودين الآخرين في جدول ردود الأفعال العكسية،
given name and surname,
الاسم المحدد واللقب،
are actually duplicated in the treatments and also the patients table.
مكررين بالفعل في العلاجات وفي جدول المرضى أيضًا.
We'll actually also want to remove these duplicate column names.
في الواقع سنرغب أيضًا في إزالة أسماء الأعمدة المكررة هذه.
Duplicate column names can be found more generally in Pandas,
يمكن العثور على أسماء الأعمدة المكررة بشكل أكثر عمومًا في Pandas،
using these following code.
باستخدام هذا الكود التالي.
This first line creates a list of all of
ينشئ هذا السطر الأول قائمة من كل
the column names across the whole data set, all three tables worth.
أسماء الأعمدة على مستوى مجموعة البيانات بالكامل، كل الجداول الثلاث تستحق.
Puts it into a series.
ضعوها في سلسلة.
Then we use the dot_duplicated method on
ثم سنستخدم طريقة dot_duplicated على
that series and we see that given name and surname are duplicated.
تلك السلسلة ونرى أن الاسم المحدد واللقب مكررين.
This list, then the data frame,
هذه القائمة، ثم إطار البيانات،
returns a list of all of the columns in the data frame.
تسترجع قائمة من كل الأعمدة في إطار البيانات.
So with these duplicate given name and surname columns removed,
لذلك، بإزالة أعمدة الاسم المحدد واللقب المكررة،
as well as the other two tidiness issues fixed,
بالإضافة إلى إصلاح مشكلتي الترتيب الآخرتين،
our final tidy data set should look like this.
ستبدو مجموعة البيانات النهائية المرتبة هكذا.
Two tables, patients, treatments,
جدولان، المرضى والعلاجات،
with the only shared column between the two being patient ID.
مع عمود معرّف المريض الوحيد المشترك بينهما.
It's best practice to have the ID as one primary identifier across tables,
هذا أفضل الممارسات أن يكون لديكم ID كمعرف رئيسي على مستوى الجداول،
because ID won't change. Name could change.
لأن ID لن يتغير. من الممكن أن يتغير الاسم.
For example, if someone legally changes their name via marriage or something.
على سبيل المثال، إذا غيّر شخص ما اسمه قانونيًا عن طريق الزواج أو شيء آخر.
So having given name and surname in one table only,
لذلك وجود اسم محدد ولقب في جدول واحد فقط،
means you only have to update these columns in one table.
يعني أنه عليكم فقط تحديث هذه الأعمدة في جدول واحد.
Consolidating these three tables as they currently stand,
دمج هذه الجداول الثلاثة بصورتها الحالية،
patients, treatments, adverse reactions,
المرضى والعلاجات وردود الفعل العكسية،
into the two displayed here,
في الاثنين المعروضين هنا،
requires joining, which is something you'll do in lesson four of this course.
يتطلب الربط، وهذا ما سنفعله في الدرس الرابع من هذه الدورة التدريبية.